Every day, Approximately 361 thousands babies are born.
That is, 250 babies come into this world
Every Single Minute.
this is you,
or the person sits next to you.
Mothers start out protecting their babies
by keeping them safe in their bellies.
Mothers are also fighters. They fight against the challenges they face in each stage of pregnancy.
The toughest challenge is at the very beginning
of pregnancy.
This is Nausea and Vomiting.
80% of pregnant women suffer from both
nausea and vomiting during the first trimester,
which lasts approximately 1~4 months.
75% of women with Nausea and Vomiting exhibit
at least two episodes per day. Each lasts
on average 1-4 hours.
Yes, round-the-clock nausea and vomiting can
leave mothers exhausted.
And yet, most pregnant women still have to
work despite the sickness and discomfort.
Working mothers, especially those who work
for long hours or devote intensive labor,
can often encounter symptoms of nausea and
vomiting in the middle of their work days,
finding themselves unable to rest.
Fortunately, nausea and vomiting have consistent
daily patterns of timing, frequency and duration.
Therefore, recording the pattern enables
them to predict symptom-free intervals and
better prepare their daily lives in an active
manner.
Here comes Dot-it, the daily recorder,
planner, and time manager, a tool to minimize
inconvenience that mothers face when nausea
and vomiting occur during pregnancy.
We offer a simple recording method, with visualization
of each individual's pattern of nausea
and vomiting, aiming to help them schedule
their routines properly and efficiently.
Let's see how they work.
First, pregnant mothers record their symptoms
through a simple method of acupressure using
Dotter, a wearable device that fits on
their wrist.
This traditional Chinese medicinal technique
of acupressure can help relieve nausea and vomiting.
Whenever mothers feel the onset of nausea
and vomiting, they press the button on the
band, which will, in turn, provide gradual
and steady pressure on the wrist.
When users begin to have a sense of relief,
they release the button, and Dot-it will measure
the duration as well as their physical location
when having the symptoms.
The system allows users to either confirm
or edit their records, and have them saved
on their smartphones.
Based on the previous record, Dot-it interprets
the data into visualized information where
mothers can explore the trend and pattern
in terms of hour, day, week and month.
Last but not least, the schedule builder.
It assists mothers in planning their calendar
in accordance with their existing records
to better manage upcoming events. .
Mothers can also import events from other
calendar apps and, if necessary, reschedule
them to a more appropriate time and location.
In all, with our Dot-it in hand, mothers can
expect their new babies peacefully and gracefully,
just as it is.